<resources>
    <string name="app_name">iInfo</string>
    <string name="university">University</string>
    <string name="hospital">Hospital</string>
    <string name="restaurant">Restaurant</string>
    <string name="travel">Travels</string>
    <string name="bank">Banks</string>
    <string name="splash">Welcome</string>


    <string name="du">University of Dhaka</string>
    <string name="dmc">Dhaka Medical College and Hospital</string>
    <string name="buet">Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology</string>
    <string name="nsu">North South University</string>
    <string name="aiub">American International University-Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="aust">Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology</string>
    <string name="ewu">East West University</string>
    <string name="brack">BRAC University</string>
    <string name="uap">University of Asia Pacific</string>
    <string name="daffodil">Daffodil International University</string>
    <string name="iub">Independent University, Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="ulab">University of Liberal Arts Bangladesh</string>


    <string name="square">Square Hospital</string>
    <string name="ibn_sina">Ibn Sina Hospital</string>
    <string name="city_hospital">City Hospital</string>
    <string name="labaid">Labaid Specialized Hospital</string>
    <string name="popular">Popular Medical College Hospital</string>
    <string name="appollo">Apollo Hospitals Dhaka</string>


    <string name="bar_b_q">Bar B Q Tonite</string>
    <string name="sabroso">Sabroso</string>
    <string name="nandos">Nandos Dhanmondi</string>
    <string name="takeout">Takeout Dhanmondi</string>
    <string name="handi">Handi</string>


    <string name="more_info">For more information......</string>
    <string name="hospital_website">Website  :</string>
    <string name="facebook">Facebook : </string>


    <string name="du_details1">The University of Dhaka (Bengali: ঢাকা বিশ্ববিদ্যালয় and also known as
        Dhaka University or simply DU) is the oldest university in modern Bangladesh. The university is ranked number
        one on the Bangladesh University Ranking 2017. Established in 1921 during the British Raj, it has made
        significant contributions to the modern history of Bangladesh. After the Partition of India, it
        became the focal point of progressive and democratic movements in Pakistan. Its students and teachers played
        a central role in the rise of Bengali nationalism and the independence of Bangladesh.</string>

    <string name="du_details2">The university distinguished alumni include Fazlur Rahman Khan (pioneer of modern structural
        engineering), Muhammad Yunus (winner of the 2006 Nobel Peace Prize, pioneer of Microcredit), Muhammad Shahidullah
        (famous educator, philologist, and linguist), Natyaguru Nurul Momen (the pioneer trailblazer of progressive
        culture, theatre, literature, performing arts, philosophy and arts; who was both an early student and a teacher
        as well, of Dhaka University), Serajul Islam Choudhury (the country's leading public intellectual and writer),
        Rehman Sobhan (social democratic economist), Mohammad Ataul Karim (physicist), Abul Fateh
        (one of the founding fathers of South Asian diplomacy), Buddhadeb Bose (20th-century Bengali poet),
        and Sheikh Mujibur Rahman (the founding father of Bangladesh).
        It also enjoyed associations with Satyendra Nath Bose, Vijayaraghavan, and Kazi Nazrul Islam.</string>

    <string name="du_details3">Today, it is the largest public university in Bangladesh, with a student body of 33,000
        and a faculty of 1,800.It was identified by AsiaWeek as one of the top 100 universities in Asia. However,
        since the 1990s,the university has suffered from intensely politicized, partisan, and violent campus politics
        promoted by Bangladesh's political parties</string>


    <string name="dmc_details1">The college original building was built before the Partition of Bengal of 1905; being used,
        as of 1904, as the secretariat (headquarters) of the newly formed provinces of East Bengal and Assam; then,
        in 1921, turned over to the University of Dhaka, which was founded that year. At that time a part of the huge
        building was used as the university medical center, another part as the students' dormitory and the rest
        as the office of the administrative wing of the Arts faculty.

        In 1939, the Dhaka university council requested that the British Government establish a separate medical college
        in Dhaka. The proposal was postponed because of the onset of the Second World War.</string>

    <string name="dmc_details2">During World War II the medical center building became an American armed forces hospital.
        The Americans vacated the building at the end of the war.

        Finally, Dhaka Medical College was established in 1946, and the college began admitting students.
        Academic classes started on 10 July which is celebrated as "DMC DAY". The 1st year, beginning class, or "Batch",
        was named K-5, 2nd year K-4, 3rd year K-3, 4th year K-2, and 5th year K-1. All the advanced students
        (K-4 through K-1) had transferred from the Calcutta Medical College, in large part because of the partition of
        India</string>

    <string name="dmc_details3">At first there were no female students, but now about half of the students are females.</string>


    <string name="buet_details1">Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (Bengali: বাংলাদেশ প্রকৌশল বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়়),
        commonly known as BUET (pronounced [bue̯eʈ]; Bengali: বুয়েট), is a public university in Bangladesh, which focuses
        on the study of engineering and architecture. Founded in 1912, it is the oldest institution for the study of
        engineering, architecture and urban planning inBangladesh.</string>

    <string name="buet_details2">Every year, around 1055 students get accepted to their undergraduate programs to study
        engineering, architecture, and urban planning. Of the 10,000 candidates selected to write the undergraduate
        admission test from an initial application pool of over 10,000 applicants, only about the top 10% are admitted.
        Around 1000 graduate students are accepted into their Masters and PhD programmes on an annual basis.
        The total number of teachers is around 600. With the construction of new academic buildings, an auditorium complex,
        and halls of residence, the university has continued to expand over the last three decades. BUET has been ranked
        135th among the Asian universities in the 2018 edition of QS World University Rankings.</string>

    <string name="buet_details3">Dacca Survey School was established in 1876 as a survey school at Nalgola,
        west of the current Sir Salimullah Medical College campus, in Old Dhaka by the then Government of
        Bengal under British Raj.[5] It offered a survey course of two years to train land surveyors, at the end
        of which students competed at the Sub-Overseer examination. According to a report on public instruction in Bengal,
        on 31 March 1903, Dacca Survey School had 117 students of which 103 were Hindus and 14 were Muslims. In 1908,
        the school started to offer diploma degrees. Khwaja Ahsanullah, a philanthropist and member of the
        Dhaka Nawab Family, endowed donations for developing the survey school. After his death in 1901, his son,
        the then Nawab of Dhaka, Khwaja Salimullah released 112,000 rupees grant in 1902 in accordance.
        As an acknowledgement of this contribution, the school was renamed to Ahsanullah School of Engineering.</string>


    <string name="nsu_details1">North South University (Bengali: নর্থ সাউথ বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়, also known as NSU) is the first
        non-government university in Bangladesh. Its Business School is also the first in Bangladesh to receive
        American accreditation from ACBSP.</string>

    <string name="nsu_details2">The government of Bangladesh approved the establishment of North South University in 1992
        under the Private University Act (PUA) 1992 (now replaced by PUA 2010). The university was formally inaugurated
        on 10 February 1993, by Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.</string>

    <string name="nsu_details3">The university ranked 1st among the private universities and 12th among all the
        universities in research output on the Bangladesh University Ranking 2017</string>


    <string name="aiub_details1">American International University-Bangladesh (Bengali: আমেরিকান ইন্টারন্যাশনাল ইউনিভার্সিটি-বাংলাদেশ),
        commonly known as AIUB is an accredited and renowned private university located at Kuratoli Road, Kuril in Dhaka,
        Bangladesh. The university is an independent organization with own Board of Trustees. It offers several degree
        programs at graduate and undergraduate level from four faculties, particularly in the field of engineering and
        business studies.</string>

    <string name="aiub_details2">The university was established in 1994 as AMA International University Bangladesh,
        a joint venture between AMA Computer University of the Philippines, and local sponsor Anwarul Abedin.
        Regular academic classes started in 1995. AMA Computer University later left the partnership, and in 2001
        the university was renamed American International University-Bangladesh..</string>

    <string name="aiub_details3">The University is located at Kuratoli Road, Khilkhet, Dhaka. The campus area is about
        30 acres (12 ha). A total building area of 1,300,000 square feet (120,000 m2) is being utilized for academic
        programs both undergraduate and graduate. The construction of main academic building is under-process.
        Currently, AIUB operates it's all academic activities in 7 annex buildings. The library will be shifted to the
        iconic round-shaped building very soon.</string>


    <string name="aust_details1">Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology (Bengali: আহ্ছানউল্লা বিজ্ঞান ও প্রযুক্তি বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়)
        or commonly known as AUST is the first non-government engineering university to be established in Bangladesh.
        The University is considered as one of the finest engineering universities and the leading non-government
        engineering university in Bangladesh, which was founded by the Dhaka Ahsania Mission in 1995.
        Dhaka Ahsania Mission is a non-profit voluntary organization in Bangladesh. The Mission was established in 1958
        by Khan Bahadur Ahsanullah.</string>

    <string name="aust_details2">The permanent Campus of the University has been built on 5-bighas (1.6 acres) of land
        at Tejgaon Industrial Area which is located in the heart of Dhaka City. The land use in this area is quickly
        changing from an industrial area to a commercial area. The 10-storied building including 2-level basement has a
        total floor area of more than 4 lac sq.ft.</string>

    <string name="aust_details3">Continuous power and water supply is ensured by its own two generators, each of 1000 KVA,
        2500 KVA sub-station and 4-inch Dia. deep tube-well. The campus also provides facilities for co-curricular
        activities like common rooms (male and female), indoor game rooms, etc. as well as space for car parking and heavy
        machinery labs in the basements.</string>


    <string name="ewu_details1">East West University (Bengali: ইস্ট ওয়েস্ট বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়, also known as EWU),
        is a private university located in Aftabnagar, Dhaka of Bangladesh</string>

    <string name="ewu_details2">The culture of private universities in Bangladesh started in the early 1990s.
        During that period, the government felt that the existing public universities were not sufficient to meet the
        demand for tertiary education in the country. Moreover, to maintain their quality of education, most of the
        public universities in Bangladesh kept themselves selective and as a result, each year a large number of students
        failed to get admitted into higher educational institutions.</string>

    <string name="ewu_details3">These issues led the government to permit the establishment of private universities,
        and on 9 August 1992, the Private University Act (Act 34) 1992 was passed.</string>

    <string name="brack_details1">BRAC University (BRACU) is a private University in Bangladesh.
        It was founded as a branch of the BRAC organization by Fazle Hasan Abed in 2001 under the Private University Act,
        1991.</string>

    <string name="brack_details2">Fazle Hasan Abed, a Bangladeshi social worker is the founder of BRAC University</string>

    <string name="brack_details3">The campus of BRACU is located at Mohakhali, Dhaka. The university is also building its
        permanent campus located at Pragati Sarani, Dhaka. The university is supposed to shift to its permanent
        campus by 2021.</string>

    <string name="uap_details1">University of Asia Pacific - UAP (ইউনিভার্সিটি অব এশিয়া প্যাসিফিক) is a private university
        located at Dhaka, Bangladesh</string>

    <string name="uap_details2">University of Asia Pacific (UAP) was established in 1996 as a private university under
        the Private University Act 1992. Its curriculum has been approved by The University Grants Commission of the
        Government of the Peoples Republic of Bangladesh. The university started its operation in the first semester of
        classes in 1996, and offered four-year bachelor's degree programs in Computer Science and Technology and Business
        Administration only. Now UAP offers undergraduate programs in English, Law, Architecture, Business Administration,
        Civil Engineering, Computer Science and Engineering, Electrical and Electronic Engineering and Pharmacy.</string>

    <string name="uap_details3">UAP has been sponsored by University of Asia Pacific Foundation, a non-profit,
        non-commercial organisation based in Dhaka, Bangladesh.</string>


    <string name="daffodil_details1">Daffodil International University (DIU; Bengali: ড্যাফোডিল আন্তর্জাতিক বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়])
        is a co-educational private university located in Dhanmondi, Dhaka, Bangladesh. It was established on 24 January
        2002 under the Private University Act, 1992.</string>

    <string name="daffodil_details2">DIU is the first university in Bangladesh to have signed the UN Commitment to
        Sustainable Practices of Higher Education Institutions</string>

    <string name="daffodil_details3">The university was established in 2002 with the approval of the University
        Grants Commission (Bangladesh) and the Government of Bangladesh's Ministry of Education.</string>


    <string name="iub_details1">Independent University, Bangladesh (Bengali: ইন্ডিপেন্ডেন্ট বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়) or IUB is a
        university located in Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka, Bangladesh. The business school of the university has received
        American accreditation from ACBSP. It was established in 1993 by the Private University Act, 1992.</string>

    <string name="iub_details2">The school offers an undergraduate Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA) degree.
        Available areas of concentration are accounting, finance, general management, human resource management,
        international business, management information systems, and marketing.</string>

    <string name="iub_details3">The school offers an MBA degree. Students are allowed up to five years from the date of
        initial enrollment to complete the degree requirements. It is possible to finish the program within five
        semesters by taking the maximum course load, or within three semesters if students have waivers or transfer
        courses. Available areas of concentration are: banking, finance, human resources management, and marketing.</string>


    <string name="ulab_details1">University of Liberal Arts Bangladesh (Bengali: লিবারেল আর্টস বিশ্ববিদ্যালয় বাংলাদেশ) (ULAB)
        is a private liberal arts-based University in Dhanmondi, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</string>

    <string name="ulab_details2">Founded in February 2002, permission to open was received from the University
        Grants Commission (UGC) of Bangladesh in November 2003, pursuant to the Private University Act 1992.</string>

    <string name="ulab_details3">ULAB incorporates the values of Liberal Arts and Sustainability into its curricula,
        through its General Education Department and its Center for sustainable development (CSD). ULAB is a
        research-intensive University, with multiple research opportunities for its faculty
        members and students</string>


    <string name="square_details1">Square Hospitals Limited is a 400 beds tertiary care hospital and the leading contributor of private
        healthcare services in Bangladesh. This has been achieved only through consistent commitment to improving
        the lives of people through utmost service excellence since its inception on 16th December 2006. Square
        Hospital is one of the ventures of Square Group which is the top business group of the country. The
        reputation of Square Hospital is the result of quality clinical outcome and comprehensive care, made
        achievable through world class integrated healthcare facilities by highly trained professionals. Thus,
        Square Hospitals strives to meet patients’ standards through quality healthcare and making a difference
        in their lives.</string>

    <string name="square_details2">This hospital is an affiliate partner of Methodist Healthcare, Memphis, Tennessee, USA; Christian Medical
        College-Vellore, India; Sing Health and Raffles Hospital, Singapore.</string>

    <string name="square_details3">The outpatient department (OPD) of the hospital can serve up to 1800 patients daily, through 100+
        consultation rooms. The outpatient services are open daily, except Friday, in a convenient morning,
        afternoon and late evening hours. Other than that our ER (Emergency dept) is fully operational 24/7
        round the year. Square Hospital has almost all departments of medical service under one roof which
        enable us to deliver proper integrated services to our patients.</string>

    <string name="ibn_sina_details1">Ibn Sina was born in 980 C.E. in the village of Afshana near Bukhara which today is located in the far south
        of Russia. His father, Abdullah, an adherent of the Ismaili sect, was from Balkh and his mother from a
        village near Bukhara.</string>

    <string name="ibn_sina_details2">In any age Ibn Sina, known in the West as Avicenna, would have been a giant among giants. He displayed
        exceptional intellectual prowess as a child and at the age of ten was already proficient in the Quran
        and the Arabic classics. During the next six years he devoted himself to Muslim Jurisprudence, Philosophy
        and Natural Science and studied Logic, Euclid, and the Almeagest.</string>


    <string name="ibn_sina_details3">He turned his attention to Medicine at the age of 17 years and found it, in his own words, "not difficult".
        However he was greatly troubled by metaphysical problems and in particular the works of Aristotle. By chance,
        he obtained a manual on this subject by the celebrated philosopher al-Farabi which solved his difficulties.</string>

    <string name="city_hospital_details1">City Hospital Ltd started on 19-02-1999 as 20 bed Specialized Burn and Plastic Surgery Hospital at 69/I/1,
        Panthapath, Dhanmondi, Dhaka-1205, then shifted to Lalmatia, Dhaka from 15th July, 2006 as 150 beded general
        hospital including 24 bed Burn and Plastic Surgery (8 High Dependency Unit beds and 16 general beds)</string>

    <string name="city_hospital_details2">
        Presently we have different specialties like Medicine, Diabetes and Endocrinology, Gynaecology and Obstetrics,
        Neo-natology and Paediatric, Nephrology, Urology, ENT, Gastroenterology, General and Laparoscopic surgery,
        Oncology,Haemato-oncology, Neuro-medicine, Orthopaedic, Spine and Arthroscopic Surgery, Dermatology, Dental
        Surgery and Dental Implant and Physiotherapy</string>

    <string name="city_hospital_details3">This hospital also has 8 beded Intensive Care Unit (I.C.U) and 6 beded Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU)
        and Dialysis.A number of reputed and experienced physicians, surgeons and other health professionals are
        providing their best support round the clock.</string>

    <string name="labaid_details1">Labaid Group adds yet another feather in its ornate cap - Labaid Hospital commissioned on 15 July 2004.
        A new era in the field of care is dawned, a new chapter opened.</string>

    <string name="labaid_details2">Labaid Hospital - the fist international standard super-specialty hospital of the country, dedicated
        exclusively to the diagnosis and treatment of cardiovascular diseases have been built on a six storied
        building at, Dhanmondi - a commercial cum residential hub of Dhaka City, covering a floor space of more
        than 100000 sq. feet.</string>

    <string name="labaid_details3">Equipped with most modern and state-of-the-art equipment and machineries, the Labaid Hospital makes a
        solemn commitment to the patients of the country - a commitment to maintain mastery and marvel in acre,
        to be compassionate and respectful to patients' beliefs and values and to make sound decision in the interest
        of the patients.</string>

    <string name="appollo_details1">Apollo Hospitals Dhaka is the only JCI Accredited 425-bed multi-disciplinary super-specialty tertiary care
        hospital in Bangladesh, confidently providing comprehensive health care with the latest medical, surgical
        and diagnostic facilities. These services are provided by expert medical professionals, skilled nurses and
        technologists using state-of-the-art technology. The hospital started its operation on April 16, 2005 with
        a mission to provide high quality international standard healthcare which will meet the needs and exceed the
        expectations of the people of Bangladesh. It is an eleven-storied building built on four acres of land with
        435,000 square feet floor space, which was constructed with assistance of renowned architecture company Smith
        Group, USA. The hospital is a joint project of Apollo Hospitals Enterprise Limited and STS Holdings Limited
        (STS Group).</string>

    <string name="appollo_details2">Apollo Hospitals Dhaka has all the characteristics of a world-class hospital with wide range of services and
        specialists, equipments and technology, ambience and service quality. The hospital is a showcase of synergy
        of medical technology and advances in IT through paperless medical records. The skilled nurses, technologists
        and administrators of Apollo Hospitals Dhaka, aided by state-of-the-art equipments, provide a congenial
        infrastructure for the medical professionals in providing healthcare of international standards.</string>

    <string name="appollo_details3">Since its inception to date, approximately 6,60,116 patients have registered with Apollo Hospitals Dhaka and
        over 25,14,152 patients have availed out-patient consultation across over 29 disciplines. The hospital is the
        first and only in Bangladesh to get accredited by Joint Commission International (JCI), which reassures its
        continued commitment to the highest quality international standard of healthcare in the region. We are not
        only about cutting-edge technology and performance-driven skill of our doctors and nurses, but we are also
        about hope, as symbolized by the flames of hope in the torch on our logo.</string>

    <string name="popular_details1">Since its inception in 2010 Popular Medical College has been engaged in producing
        "doctors with a difference capable of taking the charge of the future". It is at the verge of fulfillment of
        its commitment and the 1st batch of the students will appear in final professional examination of the
        university in January 2016.</string>

    <string name="popular_details2">The College has always emphasized on quality teachers, teaching materials
        and student friendly environment.</string>

    <string name="popular_details3">Dr. Mostafizur Rahman a young medical graduate managed to get transferred to Dhaka from the Thana Health
        complex plotting to enable him to pursue a carrier in Surgery. He was posted in Central Pathology Laboratory
        of Dhaka Medical College. Gradually he developed an interest in pathology and continued his service there.</string>

</resources>
